<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Wolfie</title>
    <link>https://wolf1e.ga/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Wolfie</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 05 Apr 2022 18:06:00 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://wolf1e.ga/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Ubuntu Touch on the Google Pixel 3a XL | Is it usable?</title>
      <link>https://wolf1e.ga/posts/2022/04/ubuntu-touch-on-the-google-pixel-3a-xl-is-it-usable/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Apr 2022 18:06:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://wolf1e.ga/posts/2022/04/ubuntu-touch-on-the-google-pixel-3a-xl-is-it-usable/</guid>
      <description>Ubuntu Logo
Hey guys, it has been a long time since I last posted on this blog. There are many reasons for that, but I will not get into them. I recently tried out Ubuntu Touch on my Google Pixel 3a XL, and I thought I would give it a review.
At the time of writing, I was testing this out on OTA-22 with installer version 0.9.5. Some of my complaints may have been fixed in a newer update.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fedora on Surface Pro 2</title>
      <link>https://wolf1e.ga/posts/2021/07/fedora-on-surface-pro-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jul 2021 17:30:44 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://wolf1e.ga/posts/2021/07/fedora-on-surface-pro-2/</guid>
      <description>Fedora Logo
I decided to try Fedora 34 on my Surface Pro 2, and here is my experience.
Installation Installation of Fedora was pretty easy. I just selected my disk, changed my timezone, and off it went. The Anaconda installer is really good, but I still think that certain installers are better. Everything went well, and it installed properly.
Using Fedora Using Fedora on my Surface Pro 2 was pretty cool.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ubuntu Unity in 2021. Is it actually usable?</title>
      <link>https://wolf1e.ga/posts/2021/07/ubuntu-unity-in-2021.-is-it-actually-usable/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://wolf1e.ga/posts/2021/07/ubuntu-unity-in-2021.-is-it-actually-usable/</guid>
      <description>Ubuntu Logo
I used the Ubuntu Unity desktop for a few days. Here are my thoughts about the Unity desktop in 2021.
The Good I love the Unity desktop. I used it back in 2014 and 2016 when I would try out Ubuntu from time to time. I never really dove into the power user features of it, but I liked the desktop. Around a few days ago, I decided to try it out again using Ubuntu 20.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Domain</title>
      <link>https://wolf1e.ga/posts/2021/04/new-domain/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Apr 2021 17:52:39 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://wolf1e.ga/posts/2021/04/new-domain/</guid>
      <description>Hey guys! I just wanted to let you know that I got a new domain! The existing one will still work, but from now on, I suggest using the new domain: https://wolf1e.ga.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Install Debian 10 On a Macbook (Early 2008)</title>
      <link>https://wolf1e.ga/posts/2021/02/how-to-install-debian-10-on-a-macbook-early-2008/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Feb 2021 23:07:06 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://wolf1e.ga/posts/2021/02/how-to-install-debian-10-on-a-macbook-early-2008/</guid>
      <description>Debian Logo
After reinstalling Debian 10 on my Macbook 4,1, I realized that I made a few mistakes in my guide. This post is a tutorial on how to properly install Debian 10 on a Macbook 4,1.
Installation When you go through the installation process, choose graphical install. You need to have a secondary mouse, as the trackpad won&amp;rsquo;t work during the install, and it won&amp;rsquo;t work very well after the install.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Airpods 1st Generation First Impressions</title>
      <link>https://wolf1e.ga/posts/2021/02/airpods-1st-generation-first-impressions/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Feb 2021 18:22:17 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://wolf1e.ga/posts/2021/02/airpods-1st-generation-first-impressions/</guid>
      <description>Airpods (Photo by PCMag)
Hello guys! I have been trying out the Airpods 1st generation for around a week now, and I have a few things to say. Let&amp;rsquo;s get right into it!
The Good The Airpods are really nice. The integration with my iPhone 7 is great because I get to use the battery widget. I also like the popup that appears that tells me the case battery percentage and the Airpods themselves.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[OUTDATED] How to Run Newer Versions of macOS on Unsupported Macs</title>
      <link>https://wolf1e.ga/posts/2021/02/outdated-how-to-run-newer-versions-of-macos-on-unsupported-macs/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Feb 2021 20:30:09 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://wolf1e.ga/posts/2021/02/outdated-how-to-run-newer-versions-of-macos-on-unsupported-macs/</guid>
      <description>This post is outdated. See the Github Gist for an up to date guide.
Hello guys! This post is a guide on what macOS versions you can run on a Unsupported Mac and what patcher to use. If you have any issues with the patchers in this post, feel free to join this discord server, and they will help you out. Anyways, enjoy the post!
Mountain Lion (10.8) Mountain Lion Banner</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[UPDATE] Transitioning Blog</title>
      <link>https://wolf1e.ga/posts/2021/02/update-transitioning-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Feb 2021 11:38:21 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://wolf1e.ga/posts/2021/02/update-transitioning-blog/</guid>
      <description>Since I now have this new website where I can blog, I will gradually transition my current blog to this website. If you didn&amp;rsquo;t already know, my blog is wolfiestech.blogspot.com. I will be uploading posts from that blog to here.
UPDATE: I have finished uploading the posts from my old blog to here. Now, you don&amp;rsquo;t need to visit that site again.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First Post</title>
      <link>https://wolf1e.ga/posts/2021/02/first-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Feb 2021 09:59:26 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://wolf1e.ga/posts/2021/02/first-post/</guid>
      <description>Hello world! This is my first post! Pretty cool!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Experience with Ubuntu On My Surface Pro 2</title>
      <link>https://wolf1e.ga/posts/2021/02/my-experience-with-ubuntu-on-my-surface-pro-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://wolf1e.ga/posts/2021/02/my-experience-with-ubuntu-on-my-surface-pro-2/</guid>
      <description>Ubuntu 20.04 Desktop (Screenshot by OMG! Ubuntu!)
A while ago, I decided to try out Ubuntu on my Surface Pro 2. I thought that since my sister&amp;rsquo;s laptop ran Kubuntu so well, I figured that I should give Ubuntu a try on my Surface Pro 2. I also run Debian on my main machine, so I figured that Ubuntu wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be too bad to try.
Installation Installation wasn&amp;rsquo;t hard. I booted into the USB drive after repeatedly trying to boot from it.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
